<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>
<configuration>
  <property>
    <name>node-scheduler.include-coordinator</name>
    <value>false</value>
    <description>
      Allow scheduling work on the coordinator. For larger clusters, processing
      work on the coordinator can impact query performance because the machine’s
      resources are not available for the critical task of scheduling, managing
      and monitoring query execution.
    </description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>http-server.http.port</name>
    <value>8081</value>
    <description>
      Specifies the port for the HTTP server. Presto uses HTTP for all
      communication, internal and external
    </description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>task.max-memory</name>
    <value>1GB</value>
    <description>
      The maximum amount of memory used by a single task (a fragment of a query
      plan running on a specific node). In particular, this limits the number of
      groups in a GROUP BY, the size of the right-hand table in a JOIN, the
      number of rows in an ORDER BY or the number of rows processed by a window
      function. This value should be tuned based on the number of concurrent
      queries and the size and complexity of queries. Setting it too low will
      limit the queries that can be run, while setting it too high will cause
      the JVM to run out of memory.
    </description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>query.max-memory</name>
    <value>50GB</value>
    <description>
      The maximum amount of distributed memory that a query may use.
    </description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>query.max-memory-per-node</name>
    <value>1GB</value>
    <description>
      The maximum amount of memory that a query may use on any one machine.
    </description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>discovery.uri</name>
    <value>http://master.net:8081</value>
    <description>
      The URI to the Discovery server. Because we have enabled the embedded
      version of Discovery in the Presto coordinator, this should be the URI of
      the Presto coordinator. Replace http://master.net:8081 to match the host
      and port of the Presto coordinator. This URI must not end in a slash.
    </description>
  </property>

  <property require-input="false">
    <name>query.queue-config-file</name>
    <value></value>
    <description>
        Specifies the file to read the queue configuration from. See
        https://prestodb.io/docs/current/admin/queue.html for more info in the
        file and the expected options.
    </description>
  </property>
</configuration>
